git-tower.com 2019-12-02

# Tower - Privacy Policy

Last updated: May 23, 2018

## 1\. An overview of data protection

### General

The following gives a simple overview of what happens to your personal information when you visit our website. Personal information is any data with which you could be personally identified. Detailed information on the subject of data protection can be found in our privacy policy below.

### Data collection on our website

##### Who is responsible for the data collection on this website?

The data collected on this website are processed by the website operator. The operator's contact details can be found in the website's required legal notice.

##### How do we collect your data?

Some data are collected when you provide it to us. This could, for example, be data you enter on a contact form.

Other data are collected automatically by our IT systems when you visit the website. These data are primarily technical data such as the browser and operating system you are using or when you accessed the page. These data are collected automatically as soon as you enter our website.

##### What do we use your data for?

Part of the data is collected to ensure the proper functioning of the website. Other data can be used to analyze how visitors use the site.

##### What rights do you have regarding your data?

You always have the right to request information about your stored data, its origin, its recipients, and the purpose of its collection at no charge. You also have the right to request that it be corrected, blocked, or deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in the legal notice if you have further questions about the issue of privacy and data protection. You may also, of course, file a complaint with the competent regulatory authorities.

### Analytics and third-party tools

When visiting our website, statistical analyses may be made of your surfing behavior. This happens primarily using cookies and analytics. The analysis of your surfing behavior is usually anonymous, i.e. we will not be able to identify you from this data. You can object to this analysis or prevent it by not using certain tools. Detailed information can be found in the following privacy policy.

You can object to this analysis. We will inform you below about how to exercise your options in this regard.

## 2\. General information and mandatory information

### Data protection

The operators of this website take the protection of your personal data very seriously. We treat your personal data as confidential and in accordance with the statutory data protection regulations and this privacy policy.

If you use this website, various pieces of personal data will be collected. Personal information is any data with which you could be personally identified. This privacy policy explains what information we collect and what we use it for. It also explains how and for what purpose this happens.

Please note that data transmitted via the internet (e.g. via email communication) may be subject to security breaches. Complete protection of your data from third-party access is not possible.

### Notice concerning the party responsible for this website

The party responsible for processing data on this website is:

> fournova Software GmbH  
>  Lenaustraße 14  
>  70193 Stuttgart  
>  Germany

> Telephone: 0049(0)70000780079  
>  Email: info@fournova.com

The responsible party is the natural or legal person who alone or jointly with others decides on the purposes and means of processing personal data (names, email addresses, etc.).

### Revocation of your consent to the processing of your data

Many data processing operations are only possible with your express consent. You may revoke your consent at any time with future effect. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

### Right to data portability

You have the right to have data which we process based on your consent or in fulfillment of a contract automatically delivered to yourself or to a third party in a standard, machine-readable format. If you require the direct transfer of data to another responsible party, this will only be done to the extent technically feasible.

### SSL or TLS encryption

This site uses SSL or TLS encryption for security reasons and for the protection of the transmission of confidential content, such as the inquiries you send to us as the site operator. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the lock icon is displayed in your browser's address bar.

If SSL or TLS encryption is activated, the data you transfer to us cannot be read by third parties.

### Encrypted payments on this website

If you enter into a contract which requires you to send us your payment information (e.g. account number for direct debits), we will require this data to process your payment.

Payment transactions using common means of payment (Visa/MasterCard, direct debit) are only made via encrypted SSL or TLS connections. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the lock icon in your browser line is visible.

In the case of encrypted communication, any payment details you submit to us cannot be read by third parties.

### Information, blocking, deletion

As permitted by law, you have the right to be provided at any time with information free of charge about any of your personal data that is stored as well as its origin, the recipient and the purpose for which it has been processed. You also have the right to have this data corrected, blocked or deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in our legal notice if you have further questions on the topic of personal data.

### Opposition to promotional emails

We hereby expressly prohibit the use of contact data published in the context of website legal notice requirements with regard to sending promotional and informational materials not expressly requested. The website operator reserves the right to take specific legal action if unsolicited advertising material, such as email spam, is received.

## 3\. Data collection on our website

### Cookies

Some of our web pages use cookies. Cookies do not harm your computer and do not contain any viruses. Cookies help make our website more user-friendly, efficient, and secure. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and saved by your browser.

Most of the cookies we use are so-called "session cookies." They are automatically deleted after your visit. Other cookies remain in your device's memory until you delete them. These cookies make it possible to recognize your browser when you next visit the site.

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.

Cookies which are necessary to allow electronic communications or to provide certain functions you wish to use (such as the shopping cart) are stored pursuant to Art. 6 paragraph 1, letter f of DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the storage of cookies to ensure an optimized service provided free of technical errors. If other cookies (such as those used to analyze your surfing behavior) are also stored, they will be treated separately in this privacy policy.

### Server log files

The website provider automatically collects and stores information that your browser automatically transmits to us in "server log files". These are:

  * Browser type and browser version
  * Operating system used
  * Referrer URL
  * Host name of the accessing computer
  * Time of the server request
  * IP address  
These data will not be combined with data from other sources.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

### Contact form

Should you send us questions via the contact form, we will collect the data entered on the form, including the contact details you provide, to answer your question and any follow-up questions. We do not share this information without your permission.

We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent per Art. 6 (1)(a) DSGVO. You may revoke your consent at any time. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

We will retain the data you provide on the contact form until you request its deletion, revoke your consent for its storage, or the purpose for its storage no longer pertains (e.g. after fulfilling your request). Any mandatory statutory provisions, especially those regarding mandatory data retention periods, remain unaffected by this provision.

This website uses Zendesk to manage support and contact requests. Zendesk is a service provided by Zendesk, Inc., 1019 Market Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. 

For more information on Zendesk's privacy policy, please go to <https://www.zendesk.com/company/privacy>.

### Registration on this website

You can register on our website in order to access additional functions offered here. The input data will only be used for the purpose of using the respective site or service for which you have registered. The mandatory information requested during registration must be provided in full. Otherwise, we will reject your registration.

To inform you about important changes such as those within the scope of our site or technical changes, we will use the email address specified during registration.

We will process the data provided during registration only based on your consent per Art. 6 (1)(a) DSGVO. You may revoke your consent at any time with future effect. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

We will continue to store the data collected during registration for as long as you remain registered on our website. Statutory retention periods remain unaffected.

### Processing of data (customer and contract data)

We collect, process, and use personal data only insofar as it is necessary to establish, or modify legal relationships with us (master data). This is done based on Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract. We collect, process and use your personal data when accessing our website (usage data) only to the extent required to enable you to access our service or to bill you for the same.

Collected customer data shall be deleted after completion of the order or termination of the business relationship. Legal retention periods remain unaffected.

### Data transmitted when entering into a contract with online shops, retailers, and mail order

We transmit personally identifiable data to third parties only to the extent required to fulfill the terms of your contract, for example, to companies entrusted to deliver goods to your location or banks entrusted to process your payments. Your data will not be transmitted for any other purpose unless you have given your express permission to do so. Your data will not be disclosed to third parties for advertising purposes without your express consent.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

### Data transferred when signing up for services and digital content

We transmit personally identifiable data to third parties only to the extent required to fulfill the terms of your contract with us, for example, to banks entrusted to process your payments.

Your data will not be transmitted for any other purpose unless you have given your express permission to do so. Your data will not be disclosed to third parties for advertising purposes without your express consent.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

## 4\. Social media

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this website.

The interaction and information obtained through this website are always subject to the user's privacy settings for each social network.

This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

### Facebook plugins (Like & Share buttons)

Our website includes plugins for the social network Facebook, Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California 94025, USA. The Facebook plugins can be recognized by the Facebook logo or the Like button on our site. For an overview of Facebook plugins, see <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>.

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Facebook server is established via the plugin. This enables Facebook to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the Facebook "Like button" while you are logged into your Facebook account, you can link the content of our site to your Facebook profile. This allows Facebook to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to Facebook or of how Facebook uses these data. For more information, please see Facebook's privacy policy at <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>.

If you do not want Facebook to associate your visit to our site with your Facebook account, please log out of your Facebook account.

### Twitter plugin

Functions of the Twitter service have been integrated into our website. These features are offered by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. When you use Twitter and the “Retweet” function, the websites you visit are connected to your Twitter account and made known to other users. In doing so, data will also be transferred to Twitter. We would like to point out that, as the provider of these pages, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or how it will be used by Twitter. For more information on Twitter's privacy policy, please go to <https://twitter.com/privacy>.

Your privacy preferences with Twitter can be modified in your account settings at <https://twitter.com/account/settings>.

### LinkedIn plugin

Our site uses functions from the LinkedIn network. The service is provided by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

Each time one of our pages containing LinkedIn features is accessed, your browser establishes a direct connection to the LinkedIn servers. LinkedIn is informed that you have visited our web pages from your IP address. If you use the LinkedIn “Recommend” button and are logged into your LinkedIn account, it is possible for LinkedIn to associate your visit to our website to your user account. We would like to point out that, as the provider of these pages, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or how it will be used by LinkedIn.

More information can be found in the LinkedIn privacy policy at <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>.

## 5\. Analytics and advertising

The services contained in this section enable the owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of user behavior. In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service. It is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies". These are text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

Google Analytics cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

##### IP anonymization

We have activated the IP anonymization feature on this website. Your IP address will be shortened by Google within the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area prior to transmission to the United States. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to provide other services regarding website activity and Internet usage for the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with any other data held by Google.

##### Browser plugin

You can prevent these cookies being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. However, we wish to point out that doing so may mean you will not be able to enjoy the full functionality of this website. You can also prevent the data generated by cookies about your use of the website (incl. your IP address) from being passed to Google, and the processing of these data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

##### Objecting to the collection of data

You can prevent the collection of your data by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set to prevent your data from being collected on future visits to this site: Disable Google Analytics.

For more information about how Google Analytics handles user data, see Google's privacy policy: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>.

##### Outsourced data processing

We have entered into an agreement with Google for the outsourcing of our data processing and fully implement the strict requirements of the German data protection authorities when using Google Analytics.

##### Demographic data collection by Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics' demographic features. This allows reports to be generated containing statements about the age, gender, and interests of site visitors. This data comes from interest-based advertising from Google and third-party visitor data. This collected data cannot be attributed to any specific individual person. You can disable this feature at any time by adjusting the ads settings in your Google account or you can forbid the collection of your data by Google Analytics as described in the section "Refusal of data collection".

### Google Analytics Remarketing

Our websites use the features of Google Analytics Remarketing combined with the cross-device capabilities of Google AdWords and DoubleClick. This service is provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

This feature makes it possible to link target audiences for promotional marketing created with Google Analytics Remarketing to the cross-device capabilities of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick. This allows advertising to be displayed based on your personal interests, identified based on your previous usage and surfing behavior on one device (e.g. your mobile phone), on other devices (such as a tablet or computer).

Once you have given your consent, Google will associate your web and app browsing history with your Google Account for this purpose. That way, any device that signs in to your Google Account can use the same personalized promotional messaging.

To support this feature, Google Analytics collects Google-authenticated IDs of users that are temporarily linked to our Google Analytics data to define and create audiences for cross-device ad promotion.

You can permanently opt out of cross-device remarketing/targeting by turning off personalized advertising in your Google Account; follow this link: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/>.

The aggregation of the data collected in your Google Account data is based solely on your consent, which you may give or withdraw from Google per Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO. For data collection operations not merged into your Google Account (for example, because you do not have a Google Account or have objected to the merge), the collection of data is based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing anonymous user behavior for promotional purposes.

For more information and the Google Privacy Policy, go to: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>.

### Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking

This website uses Google AdWords. AdWords is an online advertising program from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google").

As part of Google AdWords, we use so-called conversion tracking. When you click on an ad served by Google, a conversion tracking cookie is set. Cookies are small text files that your internet browser stores on your computer. These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used for personal identification of the user. Should the user visit certain pages of the website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and the website can tell that the user clicked on the ad and proceeded to that page.

Each Google AdWords advertiser has a different cookie. Thus, cookies cannot be tracked using the website of an AdWords advertiser. The information obtained using the conversion cookie is used to create conversion statistics for the AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Customers are told the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, advertisers do not obtain any information that can be used to personally identify users. If you do not want to participate in tracking, you can opt-out of this by easily disabling the Google Conversion Tracking cookie by changing your browser settings. In doing so, you will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.

Conversion cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

For more information about Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking, see the Google Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.

### Facebook Pixel, Facebook Remarketing and Facebook Custom Audience

Our website measures conversions using visitor action pixels from Facebook, Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook").

These allow the behavior of site visitors to be tracked after they click on a Facebook ad to reach the provider's website. This allows an analysis of the effectiveness of Facebook advertisements for statistical and market research purposes and their future optimization.

The data collected is anonymous to us as operators of this website and we cannot use it to draw any conclusions about our users' identities. However, the data are stored and processed by Facebook, which may make a connection to your Facebook profile and which may use the data for its own advertising purposes, as stipulated in the Facebook privacy policy. This will allow Facebook to display ads both on Facebook and on third-party sites. We have no control over how this data is used.

Check out Facebook's privacy policy to learn more about protecting your privacy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>.

You can also deactivate the custom audiences remarketing feature in the Ads Settings section at <https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen>. You will first need to log into Facebook.

If you do not have a Facebook account, you can opt out of usage-based advertising from Facebook on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/>.

### HockeyApp

Functions of the HockeyApp service have been integrated into our app on macOS. HockeyApp is an analytics service provided by Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052, USA ("Microsoft"). 

HockeyApp is a service which collects crash reports. In order to improve the stability of the app, we rely on crash reports. If the user voluntarily and explicitly agrees to the transmission of a crash report after a crash of the app, information about the crash is transferred to the servers of HockeyApp and stored there for evaluation by fournova. The user can opt to provide her name and email address, however this is not required. 

If the user decides to submit a crash report, the report will include the following information: 

  * Machine Identifier.
  * Bundle identifier, bundle version, and short bundle version string of your app.
  * Device type, CPU architecture, and version of the operating system.
  * Timestamp when the crash happened.
  * A generated UUID to prevent duplicate crash reports.
  * If an exception was thrown, the plain-text class name and message value of the exception.
  * Low level crash data like instruction pointer, method or function names, signal data, pointer registers, and information about the loaded binary images.
  * We do not track any user behaviour and usage metrics. If a user participates in our beta program, crash reports will be generated and sent automatically. 

Check out Microsoft's privacy policy to learn more: <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/PrivacyStatement>.

### SmartAssembly

Functions of the SmartAssembly service have been integrated into our app on Windows. SmartAssembly is an error reporting service provided by Red Gate Software Limited ("Red Gate"), Newnham House, Cambridge Business Park, Cambridge, CB4 0WZ, United Kingdom. 

SmartAssembly is a service which collects crash reports. In order to improve the stability of the app, we rely on crash reports. If the user voluntarily and explicitly agrees to the transmission of a crash report after a crash of the app, information about the crash is transferred to the servers of Red Gate and stored there for evaluation by fournova. The user can opt to provide her name and email address, however this is not required. 

If the user decides to submit a crash report, the report will include the following information: 

  * Machine Identifier.
  * Bundle identifier, bundle version, and short bundle version string of your app.
  * Version of the operating system.
  * Timestamp when the crash happened.
  * A generated UUID to prevent duplicate crash reports.
  * If an exception was thrown, the plain-text class name and message value of the exception.
  * Low level crash data like instruction pointer, method or function names, signal data, pointer registers, and information about the loaded binary images.
  * We do not track any user behaviour and usage metrics. If a user participates in our beta program, crash reports will be generated and sent automatically. 

Check out Red Gate's privacy policy to learn more: <https://www.red-gate.com/website/legal>.

### Twitter ads conversion tracking, Twitter Remarketing and Twitter tailored audiences

Twitter Ads conversion tracking, Twitter Remarketing and Twitter tailored audiences is an analytics service provided by Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA.

The service connects data from the Twitter advertising network with actions performed on this website.

For more information on Twitter's privacy policy, please go to <https://twitter.com/privacy>.

Your privacy preferences with Twitter can be modified in your account settings at <https://twitter.com/account/settings>. You can learn more about your options to opt-out: <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405>. 

### Quora ads conversion tracking

Quora Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Quora, Inc., 650 Castro Street, Suite 450, Mountain View, CA 94041, USA. 

The service connects data from the Twitter advertising network with actions performed on this Website.

For more information on Quora's privacy policy, please go to <https://www.quora.com/about/privacy>.

### Reddit ads conversion tracking

Reddit Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Reddit, Inc., 520 3rd Street, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. 

The service connects data from the Twitter advertising network with actions performed on this Website.

For more information on Reddit's privacy policy, please go to <https://www.redditinc.com/policies/privacy-policy>.

## 6\. Newsletter

### Newsletter data

If you would like to receive our newsletter, we require a valid email address as well as information that allows us to verify that you are the owner of the specified email address and that you agree to receive this newsletter. No additional data is collected or is only collected on a voluntary basis. We only use this data to send the requested information and do not pass it on to third parties.

We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent per Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO. You can revoke consent to the storage of your data and email address as well as their use for sending the newsletter at any time, e.g. through the "unsubscribe" link in the newsletter. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

The data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used to distribute the newsletter until you cancel your subscription when said data will be deleted. Data we have stored for other purposes (e.g. email addresses for the members area) remain unaffected.

### ActiveCampaign

This website uses the services of ActiveCampaign to send newsletters. This service is provided by ActiveCampaign Inc., 1 N Dearborn, 5th Floor, Chicago, IL 60601, USA.

ActiveCampaign is a service which organizes and analyzes the distribution of newsletters. If you provide data (e.g. your email address) to subscribe to our newsletter, it will be stored on ActiveCampaign servers in the USA.

ActiveCampaign is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the US to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States.

We use ActiveCampaign to analyze our newsletter campaigns. When you open an email sent by ActiveCampaign, a file included in the email (called a web beacon) connects to ActiveCampaign's servers in the United States. This allows us to determine if a newsletter message has been opened and which links you click on. In addition, technical information is collected (e.g. time of retrieval, IP address, browser type, and operating system). It is used exclusively for the statistical analysis of our newsletter campaigns. The results of these analyses can be used to better tailor future newsletters to your interests.

If you do not want your usage of the newsletter to be analyzed by ActiveCampaign, you will have to unsubscribe from the newsletter. For this purpose, we provide a link in every newsletter we send.

Data processing is based on Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO. You may revoke your consent at any time by unsubscribing to the newsletter. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

The data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used to distribute the newsletter until you cancel your subscription when said data will be deleted from our servers and those of ActiveCampaign. Data we have stored for other purposes (e.g. email addresses for the members area) remains unaffected.

For details, see the ActiveCampaign privacy policy at <https://www.activecampaign.com/help/privacy-policy/>.

## 7\. Plugins and tools

### Adobe Typekit

Our website uses Adobe Typekit. Typekit is a service provided by Adobe Systems Incorporated, 345 Park Avenue, San Jose, CA 95110, USA (“Adobe”), which allows us to access Adobe’s font library. In order for the fonts we use to be visible to you, your browser needs to connect to a server from Adobe US and download the font required in each case. Adobe obtains the information that our website has been accessed by your IP address. The use of Typekit fonts is done in the interest of a uniform and attractive presentation of our website. This constitutes a justified interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO.

For more information about Adobe Typekit, see Adobe’s privacy policies, which can be found here: <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/typekit.html>.

### FeedPress

Our website uses FeedPress to manage RSS feeds. FeedPress is provided by Beta Et Compagnie Sarl, 2 All de Seine, 93200 Saint Denis, France. 

Feedpress allows the collection of statistics on what content is consumed via our RSS feed. 

For details, see the FeedPress privacy policy at <https://feedpress.it/privacy> and data protection policy at <https://feed.press/data-protection>.

### Google Web Fonts

For uniform representation of fonts, this page uses web fonts provided by Google. When you open a page, your browser loads the required web fonts into your browser cache to display texts and fonts correctly.

For this purpose your browser has to establish a direct connection to Google servers. Google thus becomes aware that our web page was accessed via your IP address. The use of Google Web fonts is done in the interest of a uniform and attractive presentation of our website. This constitutes a justified interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO.

If your browser does not support web fonts, a standard font is used by your computer.

Further information about handling user data, can be found at <https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq> and in Google's privacy policy at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

### Google Tag Manager

This type of service helps the website owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on this website in a centralized fashion. This results in the users' data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this data.

Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States.

Further information can be found in Google's privacy policy at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

### Google Website Optimizer

This website uses the Google Website Optimizer. The Google Website Optimizer is an A/B testing service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States.

Further information can be found in Google's privacy policy at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

### YouTube

Our website uses plugins from YouTube, which is operated by Google. The operator of the pages is YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA.

If you visit one of our pages featuring a YouTube plugin, a connection to the YouTube servers is established. Here the YouTube server is informed about which of our pages you have visited.

If you're logged in to your YouTube account, YouTube allows you to associate your browsing behavior directly with your personal profile. You can prevent this by logging out of your YouTube account.

YouTube is used to help make our website appealing. This constitutes a justified interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO.

Further information about handling user data, can be found in the data protection declaration of YouTube under <https://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.

## 8\. Hosting and backend infrastructure

This type of service has the purpose of hosting Data and files that enable this Website to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of this Website.

This website uses the hosting services provided by Heroku, Inc., 650 7th Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. 

For details, see the FeedPress privacy policy at <https://www.heroku.com/policy/privacy>.

This website also uses the hosting services provided by Engine Yard Enterprises, Inc., 401 Congress Ave, Austin, TX 78701, USA. 

For details, see the FeedPress privacy policy at <https://www.engineyard.com/policies/privacy>.

## 9\. Payment service providers

Payment processing services enable fournova to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, fournova shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.

Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the user, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

Data is transmitted to Paddle, Fastspring, and Gumroad based on Art. 6 (1)(a) (Consent) and Art. 6 (1)(b) DSGVO (Processing for contract purposes). You have the option to revoke your consent at any time with future effect. It does not affect the processing of data previously collected. 

### Paddle.com UK (Paddle.com Market Ltd) and Paddle.com Ireland (Paddle Payments Ltd)

Our order process is conducted by our online reseller Paddle.com. Paddle.com is the Merchant of Record for all our orders. Paddle provides all customer service inquiries and handles returns. Paddle is operated by Paddle.com Market Ltd., 15 Bermondsey Square, SE1 3UN London, United Kingdom and Paddle Payments Ltd, Core B, Block 71, The Plaza, Park West, Dublin 12, Ireland.

Further information about handling user data can be found in Paddle's privacy policy at <https://paddle.com/privacy>. 

### Fastspring

When you purchase our app Tower, Fastspring acts as the Merchant of Record for fournova and handles the payment processing, compliance, and end-to-end taxes. Fastspring is operated by Bright Market, LLC d/b/a FastSpring. 801 Garden St., Santa Barbara, CA 93101, USA.

Further information about handling user data can be found in Fastspring's privacy policy at <https://fastspring.com/privacy/>. 

### Gumroad

Our website accepts payments via Gumroad. The provider of this service is Gumroad, Inc., 225 Valencia Street, Suite 225, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA.

When you purchase our e-book and video courses, the payment and billing will be handled by Gumroad.

Further information about handling user data can be found in Gumroad's privacy policy at <https://gumroad.com/privacy>. 

## 10\. App Registration and Update

In order to use the app Tower, a user must first activate her copy of the app.

When activating the trial version, the following data will be submitted to our licensing system: 

  * User ID
  * Machine Identifier
  * Operating System (macOS / Windows)

In order to activate the paid version of the app, the following data will be submitted to our licensing system: 

  * Email Address
  * License Code
  * User ID
  * Machine Identifier
  * Operating System (macOS / Windows)
  * Device Name

In order to update the app to the latest version, the app checks if there is a new update available. The following data will be submitted to our update system:

  * Machine ID
  * App Version
  * Operating System
  * Version of Operating System

If you don't want this data to be submitted, please do not activate the app. You can also disable automated updating in the app settings menu. 

## 11\. Children's Privacy

We recognize the importance of protecting the privacy and safety of children. Our services are not intended for children under 16 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. Anyone under 16 should not use our services. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 16 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us as set forth below.

## 12\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

For questions, please contact us at support@git-tower.com.
